Lesedi Seleke

Midrand, Johannesburg, Gauteng • +27 69 430 2866 • selekelesedi25@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/lesediseleke-41523a150

Java Developer

Java Developer with 1 year of experience in designing and updating software systems, meeting customer needs, and ensuring functionality. Utilized Java, Spring Boot, JavaScript, React, and CSS to implement web-based applications. Achieved 100% functionality alignment with design specifications in 10 months.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Reverside Geeks4Learning • 09/2023 - 07/2024 Java Developer

- Designed and updated software systems to meet customer needs and exceed expectations.
- Checked functionality against design specifications.
- Used Java, Spring Boot, JavaScript, React, and CSS to plan, test and implement various web-based applications.

The IIE Varsity College Waterfall Career Centre • 02/2021 - 12/2022 Ambassador

- Work with Career Centre Coordinator to coordinate events and activities.
- Report on all activities
- Liaison between Ambassadors, Committee and Coordinator
- Guide members of committee
- Conduct regular meetings
- Assisted in implementing and maintaining year plan
- Distributed CC activities marketing and promotional items to engage individuals.

• Answered guest questions and provided brand and product information.

Volunteer

- Organized and supervised activities.
- Used interpersonal communication skills to convey information to others.
- Assisted with prep, set up and breakdown events.
- Implemented and developed event activities.
- Built relationships with community by offering consistent encouragement and role modelling.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Computer And Information Sciences in Application

Development The IIE Varsity College • 01/2020 - 12/2022

CERTIFICATIONS

Flowgear Technical Certification • 04/2024 - Present Flowgear

VOLUNTEERING & LEADERSHIP

The IIE Varsity College • 02/2021 - 12/2021

Volunteer • Midrand, Gauteng

SKILLS

Agile Environment, Agile Project Management, Android Studio, Cascading Style Sheet, Customer Needs, Eclipse, Entity Relationship Modelling, Event Planning, Figma Software, Functional Specification, HTML5, Hypertext Markup Language, IntelliJ IDEA, Java, Java EE, JavaScript, Kotlin, Marketing, Microservices, Microsoft Office, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, NetBeans, NoSQL, REST, Scrum Methodology, Software Development Life Cycle, Software Technical Support, Spring Boot, SQL, System Analysis and Design, System Software, TypeScript, Unified Modelling Language, Visual Studio Code, Web API, Web Service.

HOBBIES

Crochet, Gaming, Gardening, Reading, Watching video essays

REFERENCES

Mogomotsi Tshwagong • Geeks4Learning – Software Development Trainer • 011 998 1960 • mogomotsi.tshwagong@qeeks4learning.com

Nomcebo Langa • The IIE Varsity College Waterfall – Career Centre Coordinator • 076 618 6324 • nlanga@varsitycollege.co.za

Handsome Mpufo • The IIE Varsity College Waterfall – IT Head of Department • 010 224 4300 • hmpufo@varsitycollege.co.za